女子監獄 第二季 第八集
醫生建議雙側輸卵管至卵巢摘除術
The doctor recommends a bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy.
誰會不喜歡有"摘除"這個詞的手術呢
Who doesn't love a surgery with "Ooph" in it?
懲教署對這個有些限制...
The, uh, DOC has set certain limits on invasive...
不能給你做
It's not gonna happen.
你并非沒得選  我們可以繼續化療
You're not out of options. We'll stick with the chemo.
"我們"
"We"?
你卵巢里也有癌癥嗎
You got cancer in your ovaries, too?
我是你的輔導員  我是幫你渡過難關的
I'm your counselor. I'm here to help you through this.
沒什么"渡過難關"
There is no "Through this."
我會死
I'm gonna die.
別這樣  你能長命百歲呢
Hey. Come on, now. You could live for years.
-開他媽的什么玩笑  -注意語言
- That's a fucking lie. - Language!
我知道這很艱難
Look, I know this is difficult for you.
我堂兄得了肺癌  情況糟糕
My cousin had lung cancer. It didn't look good for him,
但他堅持化療
but he stuck with the chemo
現在又在奧尼昂塔修屋頂了
and now he's back fixing roofs in Oneonta.
你堂兄真是走了好運
Lucky duck, your cousin.
而我  走的是霉運
Me? Dead duck.
你得盡量保持積極  沒人知道未來如何
You have to try to remain positive. No one knows the future.
醫生知道
Doctors know the future.
他們認為我需要做手術
They think I need the surgery.
但愿我可以幫你
I wish I could help you.
但你幫不了  永遠都是如此
But it's out of your hands. It's always out of your hands.
你們都一樣
You're all the same...
沒用
useless.
羅莎  我牙里卡菜了嗎
你怕他們覺得你不帥嗎  老天啊  馬爾科
是你把菠菜放在蛋里的
說起來  這樣很好吃啊
謝謝  寶貝
等下  還真卡了菜  我幫你...
好了  完美
這個給你
天哪  馬爾科
你會做得很好的
第一次誰都會緊張  但接著你會愛上這感覺的
-知道嗎  -知道
- Okay? - Mmm-hmm. Okay.
別忘了你的墨鏡
好看嗎
Ahora si?
事前一吻  事后一吻
好了
Okay.
動手吧
-所有人都趴在地上  -好好
- Suits, on the floor! Down! - Okay!
錢放袋子里
趴著別動
Just stay down.
不要染了墨的  我可不想要藍色的錢
No dye packs. Don't want no Smurf money.
快點
快
把袋子裝滿
Fill the bag.
我們走吧
走吧  寶貝
不要
Don't!
有警衛
你他媽給我的槍怎么沒子彈
搶劫拿著空槍有什么好處
讓你看起來很酷
你不信任我
槍支很危險
要的就是危險
寶貝  別生氣嘛  看看這么多錢
你聞聞
-好棒的氣味  -寶貝  棒極了
比黑色達卡還棒
天哪
你在流血
我們得送他去醫院
他中槍了
He got hit?
有多糟  馬爾科
我們可以帶他去那個獸醫那里
We can take him to that vet.
那個獸醫在哪
為什么不去獸醫那里  安迪
馬爾科
Marco.
我們怎么辦  馬爾科  告訴我
先給我事后吻  事前一吻  事后一吻
你會沒事的
你這么堅強
為我撐住  親愛的
馬爾科
Marco?
看起來不錯嘛  紅媽  發新芽了你看
Looking good, Red. You got a green thumb. Look at this.
這不是復雜的事
It's not rocket science.
那是什么
What's that?
我在想  我可以
I was thinking I could take a
占用一點地方自己種點東西
little area for my own guys to bust out a little.
種什么
What are you planting?
蔬菜
Vegetables.
別擔心  我會親自照顧的
Don't worry, I'll take care of 'em myself.
早上過來給它們唱首歌
Come in in the morning, I'll sing 'em a little song...
每天早上嗎
Every morning?
等天暖和點兒  我就把它們移到室外
When it gets warmer, I'll move 'em outside.
你確定不會太早嗎
Are you sure it's not too early?
因為如果他們在這里長得太大
Because if they grow too big in here,
移栽可就難辦了
they might not transplant well.
不就是一點蔬菜嘛  比如西葫蘆
It's just little bitch vegetables like squash.
花椰菜可不是好處理的
Broccoli is no pussy.
別擔心  我知道自己在做什么
Don't worry, I know what I'm talking about.
這個盆對這株幼苗來說太大了
This pot is way too big for this seedling.
你得確保排水沒問題...
You gotta make sure you're getting proper drainage here...
別動
Don't!
那是吉米的盆  是豆莖
That's Jimmy's pot. It's a bean stalk.
她覺得自己要從巨人那里偷琴呢
She thought she was going to steal a harp from a giant.
整個簡直...
It was a whole... just...
好吧
Okay.
要是你擔心排水系統
If you're worried about the drainage,
不如給我買些小點的花盆
maybe you could buy me some smaller pots.
這些花盆應該沒什么問題
Yeah. They'll probably do just fine.
把你的種子給我吧  我會給你播種的
Leave your seeds. I'll get your plants going.
別了  我喜歡親力親為
Nah. Truth is, I like doing it myself.
有益身心
Therapeutic.
明天見
See you tomorrow.
干得不錯
Good job.
我得說
I have to say,
這事還挺讓人開心的
there is something gratifying about this, you know?
洗別人的衣服
Washing someone else's clothes,
為他人服務
being of service to another human being.
等你洗到
Well, just wait till you
全是大姨媽的褲子
come across some of them period-soaked panties
或者沾了屎的內褲再看你有多開心吧
or the shit stains on the undies and see how gratified you are.
我懂你的意思  蘇蘇
I get what you're saying, Soso.
拿來臟東西  再洗干凈
Taking something dirty, making it not dirty no more.
說到洗
And speaking of washing.
看到小賣部里新進了除臭劑嗎
You see they got a new kind of deodorant down at commissary?
爽身粉味兒的
Powder fresh scent.
-真的嗎  -是啊
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我找時間去看看
Yeah, I may have to go check that out.
止汗劑對人體非常不好
Guys, antiperspirant is so bad for you.
超級有毒
You know, it's completely toxic.
我們的身體應該自由呼吸
Our bodies are meant to breathe free.
呼吸  是啊
Breathe, yeah.
這話讓我希望
Yeah. You know, that makes me wish
我們這兒能有些窗
that we had some windows down
好通通風
here so we could air out the place, you know?
她們想說你很臭
Yeah, they're trying to say you stink.
真的嗎
I do?
我們知道剛來這兒不容易
We know it's hard to get out of that depression funk thing
脫離那種絕望
when you first get here but...
你很臭
You reek.
去洗澡吧
Go take a shower.
好了  塔琪  別說了
All right, Tucky. Lay off.
你說什么  琳恩  你才閉嘴
Excuse me? Leanne, you lay off.
因為我認識的琳恩會告訴這個臟妞
'Cause the Leanne I knew would've told this dirty hippie
去洗洗她的下面
to go wash her hairy pits and her parts.
但你現在想交新朋友了是嗎
But instead, you're off making new friends now, aren't ya?
怎么樣
How's that going?
感覺就不太好
Can't imagine well,
因為真朋友不會兜圈子
because a real friend doesn't have to dance around the subject.
真朋友會說實話
And a real friend just tells it like it is.
學著點兒
Watch and learn.
你聞著跟烏龜缸似的  趕緊他媽去洗個澡吧
You smell like a fucking turtle tank. Go take a fucking shower.
一個80歲老太一個月忘洗澡了
You try washing an 80-year-old woman
你卻想給她洗澡
when she's forgotten to shower for a month.
這兒出了些怪事
Strange things grow in the folds.
我們把吉米的事瞞了好多年了
We hid Jimmy's condition for years.
她到處晃的時候我們花半天去找她
Spent half our days tracking her down when she wandered,
想讓她及時趕回來點名
trying to get her back in time for count,
看著她日況愈下
watching her get worse every day.
她要怎么吃飯  要怎么照顧自己
How is she gonna eat? How is she gonna take care of herself?
她會流落街頭  然后
She'll end up on the street and then...
我猜撐不過一周
My guess, dead in a week.
別誤會  他們干的事非常惡心
Don't get us wrong, it's disgusting what they done,
而她是  曾是一個很好的女人
and she is, was, a lovely woman.
所以提前釋放只是踹了就跑
So compassionate release is really just a dump and run?
更像是踹開
More like dump and sidle
再偷偷溜走  他們就是這樣的人
away like the sneaky, shitty spiders they are.
我認識一個記者  他也許能幫忙
I know this guy, a reporter. He might be able to help.
《瘋老太獲釋》
"Demented Granny Set Free,"
可不是什么性感標題  連新聞都稱不上
ain't a sexy headline and it ain't news.
沒人關心老太太
No one gives a shit about old ladies.
我們讓別人想到他們都難逃一死
We remind everyone that they're gonna die.
我不這么看
I don't feel that way.
我覺得在老人身邊很舒服
I find it comforting to be around old people.
很高興能幫上忙
Glad we could be of service.
我奶奶快死了
My grandmother is dying.
很遺憾
Sorry to hear that.
她教我織東西
She taught me how to knit.
我給我的毛絨猴子織了一條毯子
I made a blanket for my stuffed monkey.
花了我六個月
It took me six months.
然后我媽在庭院當舊貨賣了兩角五分
And then my mother sold it at a yard sale for a quarter.
你媽可真討厭
Your mum sounds like a twat.
有時是的
She can be.
但我奶奶不是
But not my grandmother, no.
我爺爺死時
When Granddad died, she
她自學投資股票
taught herself how to invest in the stock market
變得非常在行
and got really, really good at it.
她在韋爾弗利特買了套房子
She bought herself a house in Wellfleet and...
還開始劃皮劃艇了
she started kayaking.
她以前總跟我說  "出去見見世面  帕波
She always used to say to me, "Go out and eat the world, Piper.
別為了男人在家做家庭主婦"
"Don't you get stuck at home with some man."
后面那句話我可能聽得有些片面了
I may have taken that last part too literally.
查普曼
Chapman.
我猜猜
Let me guess,
親愛的查普曼小姐  沒人能休假
"Dear Miss Chapman, no one gets furlough.
你不行  別人不行  尤其是你不行
"Not you, not anyone, but especially not you.
敬上  懲教署  差不多嗎
"Love, the DOC." Am I warm?
-你可以休假了  -真有趣
- Got your furlough. - Funny.
少諷刺了
Hey, watch the sarcasm.
我撥了幾通電話  托了一點關系
I made a few phone calls, moved the process along.
你可以去跟奶奶告別了
You get to go and say goodbye to your nana.
天哪
Oh, my God!
我的天哪
你說  你說真的嗎
Are you... Are you serious?
別提問  查普曼  道謝就好
Don't ask questions, Chapman. Just say, "Thank you."
謝謝
Thank you.
太謝謝了
非常感謝  海利先生  謝謝
Thank you, Mr. Healy. Thank you.
好了  不客氣
Okay. You're welcome.
不客氣  查普曼  不客氣
You're welcome, Chapman. You're welcome.
他剛是說"休假"了嗎
Did... Did he say furlough?
你也太聾了  親愛的  誰能休假啊
You're deaf as a post, honey. No one gets a furlough.
早上好  早  你好啊
Good morning. Morning. How are you?
早上好啊美人
Good morning, sunshine.
這是什么
What's this?
是熱可可
It's a hot chocolate.
有點甜  給我的...
A little sweet, for my...
-給你  -謝謝  喬爾
- You. - Thanks, Joel.
太燙了嗎
Was it too hot?
這里面有烈酒嗎
Is there Schnapps in this?
有
Yeah.
那這杯是我的
That one's mine.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
寶貝  這是增添風味
Babe, it's for flavor.
別叫我寶貝
Don't call me babe.
你不能回我短信就不能叫我寶貝
You can't call me babe if you can't return my texts.
我要跟你說幾次  我不發短信的
How many times do I have to tell you, I don't text.
好了  你要跟我聊天的話  就打電話吧
All right, if you wanna talk to me, call.
或者開車來我家
Or drive over to my house.
但是得半夜之后  等我室友睡著
You know, but after midnight, when my roommate's sleeping.
卡普托  你看看  看到沒  你他媽看到沒
Caputo! Look at this. Do you see this? Do you fucking see this?
你的鞋嗎  我看到了  很漂亮
Your shoe? I see your shoe. It's a nice shoe.
-很漂亮  -高跟的
- Nice? - High.
這是一雙鞋底粘了口香糖的魯布托鞋
These are fucking Louboutins with gum on the sole.
我踩到了口香糖  雙腳都沒進門呢
I stepped in gum, not two feet into the building.
囚犯哪來的口香糖  口香糖是禁運品  卡普托
Where are the prisoners getting gum? Gum is contraband, Caputo.
這貨是怎么進來
How the hell is it getting in,
被嚼  被吐在地上
chewed, dropped and stuck
然后粘在我昂貴的鞋上了
to the bottom of my very expensive shoe?
-我不知道  -所以我才擔心
- I don't know. - And that's what concerns me.
我在執行記過配額指標呢
I'm enforcing your shot quota.
我已經盡我所能了
I'm doing everything I can.
那就再加把勁  掌握控制權
Well, do better. Take control.
你  你在這兒上班嗎
You, do you work here?
-是的  女士  -別叫我"女士"
- Yes, ma'am. - Don't call me "Ma'am."
我不是來買你東西的大媽
I'm not an old lady you're bagging groceries for.
你是獄警  你的工作是執行規定
You are a correctional officer. Your job is to enforce the rules.
-你知道都有些什么規定嗎  -知道
- Do you know what the rules are? - Yes.
因為現在隨便看向哪兒
Because, right now, looking in an arbitrary direction,
都能看到大耳環和不允許化的妝
I see large earrings, I see unapproved makeup.
只有我看到了嗎  是我有透視眼嗎
Am I the only one who sees this? Do I have super vision?
我跟《第六感》里那男孩一樣
Am I like the boy in The Sixth
能看到別人看不到的東西嗎
Sense who sees infractions no one else sees?
是我走進了奈特·沙拉馬拉馬的電影
Am I in a fucking M. Night Shalamalama movie,
還是那個囚犯搽了綠色眼影
or is that inmate wearing green eye shadow?
應該是叫沙馬蘭吧
I think it's pronounced Shyamalan.
我還是先回去干活了
I, uh, better get back to work.
菲格羅亞小姐  大家都化妝
Miss Figueroa, everyone wears makeup.
很好  那我就沒瘋
Oh, good, I'm not crazy.
那你會做些什么
So are you gonna do something about it,
還是站在這里當擺設呢
or are you just here for decoration?
囚犯  等等
Inmate, hold up.
那完全沒必要
That was totally unnecessary.
我把她可憐巴巴的眼神搞得更慘兮兮了嗎
Oh, did I make her sad puppy dog eyes look even sadder?
我知道你對她有些
Look, I know you have some
愛情卡通片的感覺
kind of pathetic Love Is cartoon crush on her,
但現在不是高中了
but this isn't high school.
做好本分  不然我就另覓他人
Do your job, or I will find someone who will.
叫這人洗個澡去
And make this one take a shower.
一直累死了  我到哪睡哪
So fucking tired all the time, I fall asleep everywhere.
我跟戀尸癖似的
It's like I'm a necrophiliac.
你們想到計劃什么的了嗎
You guys come up with a plan yet, or what?
上一個想法是假裝我很胖
Last idea was to pretend I'm fat,
在掃帚柜里生下來  然后從他的假腿里偷送出去
have it in the broom closet, and then sneak it out in his leg.
他一定是在開玩笑
But I'm pretty sure he was kidding.
但他可能說到點子上了
But he could be onto something though, you know?
這里的人好像
People around here seem
總有辦法把東西弄進來
to have all sorts of ways of gettin' shit in,
也許你能想辦法反過來
so maybe you could figure out the reverse.
上面是給廚房里的  下面是我姑娘們要的
Top's extra for my kitchen, bottom's some perks for my girls.
可別出岔子
Don't want any drama.
不會的  只是生意
No drama, just business.
護士  你在采血還是給她紋身呢
Hey, lady, are you taking her blood or giving her a tattoo?
我盡力呢
I'm doing my best.
你的"盡力"爛爆了
Yeah, well, your best sucks.
也許你一會兒會開始嘔吐  就不會這么多話了
Maybe you'll start vomiting soon so you can't talk so much, yes?
趕緊把頭埋進桶里
Go stick your head in a bucket.
謝謝你捍衛我的靜脈  桶仔
Thank you for defending my veins, bucket boy.
她就是個沒用的賤人
Yeah, well, she's a useless bitch.
她是個酒鬼
She's a drunk.
你說什么呢
What are you talking about?
看著  她會在窗口把血放下
Watch, she'll drop off the blood at the window,
繞到后面放錢包的柜子
circle back to the cabinet where they keep their purses
然后背對別人
and then she'll turn her
喝點東西
back and she'll take a slug of something.
然后關掉柜子  往嘴里扔塊口香糖
Then close it up and pop a piece of gum into her mouth.
定時定點  每隔20分鐘左右
She's like clockwork, every 20 minutes or so.
我操  你一直在踩點啊
Shit! You've been casing the joint.
我們有的是時間  你又沒那么有趣
We got time here. You're not that interesting.
好吧  如果你要打劫
Okay, okay. So if you were gonna pull off a heist,
就此時此地  你會怎么做
like, in this room, right now, how would you do it?
我死前最后一次打劫嗎  這又不是電影  孩子
One last heist before I go? This isn't the movies, kid.
別這樣吧  遷就我下  我也得了癌癥呢
No, come on, humor me. I have cancer.
目標是誰  聰明鬼
Who's the mark, smartass?
女酒鬼  偷她的錢包吧
Drunky bitch. Yeah, let's steal her wallet.
行  我奉陪
Okay, fine. I'll play.
我們今天走運  來的獄警是福特
We're lucky today. I got CO Ford.
他每小時會走開去看看司機怎么樣
He actually gets off his ass to check the driver once an hour.
用時五分鐘  然后會去上個廁所
Takes five minutes. Then he takes a bathroom break.
那就是兩分鐘
So two minutes.
不錯啊
Good.
然后他會買杯咖啡  最多四分鐘
Then he takes a coffee, that's another four, tops.
前臺是個抽煙的
And the receptionist is a smoker.
她每三小時準點去摸魚
She takes a break every three hours, on the dot.
那我怎么知道哪個錢包是女酒鬼的
So how do I know which purse is Drunky's?
跟酒瓶放一塊兒的
Feel for the one with the flask.
抽煙的那個上一次摸魚是1小時15分鐘之前
Smokey's last break was one-hour-fifteen ago.
那怎么辦  我們就等著嗎
So what, do we just... We just wait?
我們等著
We wait.
你從斯坦韋路走會快一點
It'd be faster if you go down Steinway.
但那里有建筑
Except there's construction.
安迪  你得想辦法繞過去  行嗎
Andy, you gotta find a way around it, okay?
沒問題
No problem.
你倆能消停點嗎  這可是公事
Will you two stop? Hey, this is work.
那就做事啊  傻逼  我搞得定
Work now, ass-play later. I got it.
好了  聽著
Okay, listen.
銀行里有三個出納  一個保安
We're looking at three tellers and one guard.
保安我來對付  唐  你去拿錢
I'll cover the guard. Don, you do the cash. Okay?
我們得在中午前搞定
And we gotta do this before noon,
因為今天是周五  中餐后他們會加派人手
because it's Friday and they add extra people in after lunch.
你能應付保安嗎
Can you handle the guard?
這個傻逼
This fucking guy.
我能應付貝賽德銀行的那個保安嗎
Could I handle the guard in Bayside?
第一國家銀行的那兩個
The two in First National?
在康美銀行嚇尿的可不是我  對吧  唐
Wasn't me who freaked out at Commerce Bank, was it, Don?
好了
Okay.
準備好出發了嗎
We ready to roll?
走了
I'm off.
等下  還有一件事
Hold up. One more thing.
事前一吻  事后一吻
你們每次都要這樣嗎
Oh, you gotta do this every time?
這是好運
It's good luck.
靠邊停  在這里停  就是那輛車
Pull over. Pull over here. There's the car.
安迪  你干什么  我們得換車  快啊
Andy, what are you doing? We gotta do the switch! Let's go.
等一下
I need a minute.
沒時間等了  快點  沒時間休息
Papi, we don't got minutes. Come on, there's no time to rest.
羅莎
Rosa!
他好像心臟病發了
I think he's having a heart attack.
快走
Let's go.
心臟病發
求你  別這樣  親愛的
Please, don't do this, Papi. Please, okay?
我們還要去看尼亞加拉大瀑布呢
We gotta see Niagara Falls, okay?
我們還要看山貓隊的比賽呢  求你了  親愛的
We got tickets to Cats. Please, Papi. Please.
天哪  別再發生了  別又來一次
Oh, my God! This can't be happening again. Not again.
找鑰匙  我來開車
我是卡蘿爾·查普曼
Hello, you've reached Carol Chapman.
請留下姓名  電話號
Please leave your name, number,
以及簡短的留言  我會...
and an ever so brief message and I'll...
天哪  人都上哪去了
Oh, my God, where are they?
一個囚犯只能打一通電話  有人排隊的
One call per inmate. There's a line.
這都算不上是電話
That wasn't even a call.
掛上電話  重新排隊
You hung up. Get back in line.
我得給休假做些安排
I need to make arrangements for my furlough.
行吧
Fine.
維特利納太干了  綠維特利納是甜葡萄酒
Sure, it's dry for a Veltliner. Grune Veltliner is a sweet wine.
我說了他不喜歡甜白酒
I told you he doesn't like sweet whites.
所以你才沒拿到合同
That's why you didn't get the contract.
而她簡直是在講小說
Meanwhile, she's dictating a novel.
你  查普曼
You, Chapman...
那是口紅嗎
that lip gloss?
不不  我天生的唇色
No, no, no, no. These are just my lips.
那睫毛呢
What about the eyelashes?
-也是天生的  -好吧
- I was born with them. - Fine.
他不會讓我失望的
He wouldn't have let me down.
我操  這應該能點火啊
Shit. It's supposed to light on fire.
簡直是我見過的最蠢的事
It's the dumbest fucking thing I've ever seen.
你和費歇爾
Hey, am I wrong to assume
是不是湊成一對兒了
that you and Fischer have been riding the hobby horse?
我可不是八卦王  不過
I don't kiss and tell, but, uh...
我上了她
I fucked her.
才沒呢
No, you didn't.
-我抓了她的奶  -才沒呢
- I grabbed her boobs. - No, you didn't.
-真的  -真的
- No, I did! - Really?
比我厲害
It's farther than I got.
-吃醋了  -完全沒有
- Jealous? - Nah. Not at all.
現在我知道她品位很爛了
Now I know she has horrible taste.
看到沒
See?
我就說吧
Told you.
這是什么原理
How does that even work?
拜托  你才是電工的頭兒
Come on, you're head of electrical.
我知道  不過原理到底是什么
Yeah, I know, but how's that work?
盧斯奇
Luschek!
囚犯
Inmate!
這里最好有12節電池  再數一遍
There better be a dozen batteries there. Count 'em again.
一  二  三...
One, two, three...
我操  三后面是幾來著  我忘了
Fuck, man, what comes after three? I forgot.
你沒在這里抽煙吧
You haven't been smoking out here, have you?
為什么說我抽煙
Why do you assume I'm a smoker?
因為你在奧斯維戈長大
'Cause you grew up in Oswego.
我戒了  把錢都花在威士忌上了
Well, I quit. More money for whiskey.
我聞到了煙味
I smell smoke.
那是睫毛膏嗎  你怎么會有
Is that mascara? Why do you have mascara?
因為小賣部有賣
'Cause they sell it at commissary.
-好好管管你的人  -是
- Keep your people in line. - All right.
她的奶子怎么樣
Now, what are those tits like?
獄警  他們也是人  這是蘇珊·費歇爾
這些文章總是把的漫畫腰斬
That article keeps on cutting off my comic.
他們都沒腳了
Now they got no feet!
她穿了高跟鞋呢  現在我知道豬是指誰了
Oh, she's wearing heels! Now I get who the pig is.
你應該再讓她背個錢袋
You should have her holding money bags, too.
親愛的弗娜卡
"Dear Flaca,
我的室友一直在偷我貨  我該怎么處理
"My bunkie's lifting my shit. How should I handle the situation?"
不能說"貨"
You can't say, "Shit."
不然怎么說  "賤人"嗎  因為弗娜卡說
Well, can I say, "Bitch"? 'Cause here's what Flaca say,
盡量說服賤人別再偷東西
"Try to reason with the bitch to lay off the sticky fingers,
但如果她不聽
"But if she doesn't listen,
就拖她去個沒人的地方
"You know, drag her to a place where no one can see,
給她一頓胖揍
"And bash her head real good."
耶穌看到了
Jesus saw that.
這些都不能寫
You can't write any of that.
你知道管理員需要審核簡報
You know the administration needs to approve all of this.
你讓她去小賣部買把牢固的鎖吧
Why don't you tell her to go buy a sturdy lock at the commissary?
我就這意思
That's what I'm saying.
買把鎖  藏在襪子里  然后放倒那賤人
Buy a lock, stick it in a sock and slock the bitch down.
不  我們得完成這個  最晚明天必須完成
No. We have to finish this up. This has to be done by tomorrow.
不是周二才截止嗎
I thought we had till Tuesday?
我周二不在
I won't be here Tuesday.
怎么  你要請事假
Oh, what, you takin' a personal day?
不  我拿到休假了
No, I got furlough.
-真的嗎  -不
- For real? - No...
慢著  絕對不可能
Wait, no fucking way.
真的  我奶奶病了  我申請然后通過了
Yeah. My grandmother's sick. I applied and it went through.
我也申請了
I applied, too!
我還讓人給典獄長打了電話  根本屁都沒用
I even had people call the warden. That shit never works!
是啊  我幾乎都放棄了
I know. I had almost completely given up.
現在  我可以去跟她道別
Now... Now I get to go, say goodbye.
告訴她我有多愛她
Tell her how much I love her.
五分鐘內就道完別
Yo, get that shit out of the way in, like, in five minutes.
超快說完你要說的話
You know, say what you gotta say, like, super quick.
就說  "安息吧  奶奶
Then be like, "Peace, abuelita!
我會在夜店
"I'll be in the club with
點杯長島冰茶  使勁扭屁股"
my Long Island and my fatty, making it clap!"
她的白屁股可扭不起來
No way that white ass is gonna clap.
姑娘們會嫉妒你的
Girls are gonna be pissed at you.
-我現在就有點想揍你  -我也是
- I kinda wanna punch you right now. - Me, too.
你最好小心點
You better watch your back.
-你拿到休假了  查普曼  -是的
- You got furlough, Chapman? - I did.
我在天主教堂待了好多年
I've been in the Catholic Church a lot of years
老實說這是我第一次見到上帝的奇跡
and this is my first honest-to-goodness miracle.
好好利用這一次
Use it well.
我會的
I will.
我會去找我奶奶
I'm gonna go and be with my grandmother
問她所有我沒來得及問的問題
and ask her all the questions I never got to ask.
這是什么
What is that?
冰沙  甘藍菜  棗子和杏仁乳
Smoothie. Kale and dates and, uh, almond milk.
-你抽煙嗎  -不抽  但我有時會嚼煙草
- You smoke? - No, but I chew tobacco sometimes.
嚼煙草就白喝甘藍菜了  不是嗎
Chewing tobacco defeats the purpose of drinking kale, doesn't it?
我會想也許它們互相抵消
Well, I like to think that they cancel each other out, maybe.
你有什么事嗎  還是...
Um, can I help you with something? Or...
禁運品
Contraband.
我覺得自己簡直在玩"打鼴鼠"的游戲
I feel like I'm playing whack-a-mole here.
我在一處砸中了它  它又在另一處跑出來了
I beat it down in one place and it pops up in another.
你看到什么的話記得告訴我
You need to tell me if you see anything.
好的
Yeah, of course. Yeah.
想都別想保護誰
Don't you dare try to protect anyone.
我知道這很難  你在這里交到了朋友
I know it's hard. I know you make friends in this place.
-不  我沒有...  -你有  時有發生
- No, I, I don't... I don't... - You do. It happens.
有時你都沒意識到
Sometimes you don't even realize it's happening, and,
突然之間  就發現自己相信別人了
all of a sudden, you find yourself trusting somebody.
你問別人意見
You're asking somebody advice...
那個人可不是你的朋友  那個人...
That person is not your friend. That person...
怎么了
What?
我操
Fuck.
我了個大草
The fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
看看我  我還在這兒呢
Oh, hey, look at me, I'm still here.
我只是盡本分  莫里洛
I'm just doing my job, Morello.
費歇爾帶羅莎來時從來不來查崗
Fischer never came to visit when she had Rosa.
你知道她會做什么嗎
You know what she'd do?
一天結束  她會給我帶希斯酒吧
She'd bring me a Heath bar and a cold Dr.
和冷的胡椒博士
Pepper at the end of the day.
是不是超體貼
Isn't that thoughtful?
也許你來查崗時也可以這么做
Maybe you could do that when you come to check on me.
-下一小時再見  莫里洛  -好吧
- I'll see you in an hour, Morello. - Okay, fine, fine.
也許你可以就給我
Maybe you could just bring
帶個空瓶子來好讓我撒尿
me an empty bottle that I could pee into.
我不能離開這車  對吧
I can't leave the van, right?
你可以下車到后面蹲坑
Oh, you can get out and take a squat in the back
然后再上車
and then get back in.
太好了  謝謝  太感謝你了
Okay, great. Thank you. Thank you so much.
我要去廁所了
Uh, well, I'm going off to the bathroom.
真是個蠢貨
護士小姐  能來一下嗎
Nurse? Nurse? Can you come over here, please?
沒什么事吧
Is everything okay?
我的閥門好像漏了
I think my port is leaking.
沒有啊  沒什么問題
No, looks fine to me.
這戒指真漂亮
Oh, what a beautiful ring!
有多大  兩克拉嗎
What is that? Two carats?
是的
It is.
怎么  你還是珠寶賊
What, were you a jewel thief?
不  我對珠寶沒什么興趣  不過我喜歡閃閃的
Nah, that was never my main gig, but I like the bling.
-六千塊  -少了
- Six grand? - Warm.
-七千  八千  -八千五
- Seven? Eight? - Eight and a half.
我未婚夫是大型連鎖超市的地區經理
My fiance is a regional manager for Foodtown.
-他省了...  -他真厲害
- He had to save up for... - Good for him.
我有點渴了  能給我倒杯水嗎
I'm a little thirsty. Can I have some water, please?
行
Yeah, sure.
假警報
It was a false alarm.
我操啊  小屁孩
The fuck, kid?
沒想到我會為63塊錢這么激動
I never thought I'd get so excited over $63.
-才20塊  -這是你的分成
- $20? - That's your cut.
-所有事都是我干的  -整個行動是我策劃的
- I did all the work! - I was the brains of the operation.
尤瑟夫·米瑞馬迪
Yusef Miremadi.
都是她策劃的
She was the brains.
你媽媽來了
Your mom is here.
醫生要跟你們談談
The doctor needs to speak with you.
媽媽的乖寶寶
Mama's boy.
我會回來的  這可沒完
I will be back. Okay, but this is not enough.
永遠沒完
It's never enough.
五萬塊
Fifty grand!
還沒到家呢  先別激動
We're not home yet. Cool it.
這么認真
Oh, so serious.
來吧  事前一吻  現在該事后吻了
Come on, we kissed before. It's time for the after kiss.
你知道我不會這么做的
You know I won't do that.
別  這會帶來霉運
No. It's bad luck.
別鬧了  我們還要再開一段路
Cut it out. We gotta drive more!
就在這里停車
Pull over right here.
你因為搶劫而性致高昂  行
You're all hot from the job? Fine.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我不想操  我想搶銀行
I don't wanna fuck now. I wanna rob that bank.
-我們才剛搶過  -再搶一家
- We just did one. - Let's do one more!
我們對這家銀行一無所知  好嗎
We don't know nothing about that bank. Okay?
我們不知道誰在工作  警報器在哪
We don't know who's working, where the alarms are. All right?
簡直瘋了  我不干
This is crazy. I'm not doing it.
我不需要你
Well, I don't need you.
你需要我的  羅莎
Yes, you do need me, Rosa.
你干什么
What are you doing?
看看你  因為拿到休假覺得自己碉堡了
Look at you thinking you're all hot shit 'cause you got furlough.
我真該給你剃個短短頭
I ought to give you a skullet.
什么是短短頭
What's a skullet?
就是光頭只留小辮兒
A mullet with the top shaved.
就這樣吧  我家人以為我出去會是彪悍的重罪犯
Well, you might as well. My family is expecting a hardened felon.
讓他們滿意一次也好
It would be nice to meet their expectations for once.
你在自由世界有48小時  有宏偉計劃了嗎
You got 48 hours in the free world, kid. You got big plans?
跟我的家人在一起
Be with my family...
看著我奶奶過世
watch my grandmother fade away.
別這樣  太浪費了
Oh, come on. That can't be it.
你會跟你丈夫一起嗎
You gonna stay with your husband?
不  他不是我丈夫
No... Well, he's not my husband.
我都不知道我們還是不是朋友
And I don't even know if we're friends anymore.
我想到我的家
I mean, when I think of my home,
我想到我們一起住的地方
I think of where we lived together,
但我不住在那里了
but I don't live there anymore.
我都不知道我的東西還在不在那里
I don't even know if my stuff is still there.
我的乳液還在不在洗手臺上
I don't even know if my lotions are on the sink,
還是他全把我的東西收進袋子里
or if he took them all and he put them in a bag
漏得整個都是了
and they're all just leaking all over each other.
還是就把我的東西留在原處
Or if he just left them there.
他可千萬別改變  或者做出  或者注意任何事
God forbid he should change, or do, or notice anything.
我倆現在的關系有點棘手
Things are a little complicated between us right now.
你怎么做到的  查普曼
So, how'd you do it, Chapman?
你給海利什么"好處"了嗎
Did you give Healy a little reach-around?
天哪  才沒有
God, no, no. No!
沒有  他們可能真是終于同情我了
No, I think that they might've finally taken pity on me.
我將要失去我愛的人
I mean, I'm about to lose somebody that I love.
也許  這所監獄還是有點良心的
Maybe, maybe, this prison has a heart after all.
放屁吧
Bullshit!
我申請了兩次
I applied twice.
我丈夫進行開胸手術
When my husband had open heart
以及我第一個孫子出生時
surgery and for the birth of my first grandchild.
他們讓我滾蛋
They told me to go fuck myself.
從沒抱過那孩子  但我真的很想抱
Never held the baby. And I love me some baby holding.
我也申請過
I applied, too.
沒同意
Nothing.
申請干什么
What for?
我父親進行了移植肺臟  但排斥了
My father had a lung transplant that didn't take.
我變性后咱倆就沒說過話  他真的很拗
We hadn't spoken since I transitioned. He was a real hard-ass.
但最后  他開始找我
But in the end, he started asking for me.
他甚至叫我的新名字  索菲婭
He even used my new name, Sophia.
人之將死其言也善
People get soft, you know, when they dying.
如果我當時見到他了  或許...
If I could've seen him, I don't know...
會有種了卻心結的感覺
may have felt like closure.
但我們這輩子是沒多少機會了  不是嗎
But we don't get a lot of that in this life now, do we?
這是我后悔清單里的一項
Add it to my list of regrets.
但是奶奶  也很重要
But grandmothers, they important, too.
你干什么
What are you doing?
找什么呢
What are you looking for?
說話啊
Use your words.
在哪
Where is it?
什么  香菜  西葫蘆嗎
What? The cilantro, the squash?
你是要砸碎每個花盆嗎
Are you gonna smash every pot?
必須的
You bet your ass.
這次你最后一次騙我了  紅媽
This is the last time, Red, you pull one over on me.
行吧  讓我幫你
All right. Let me help you.
怎么  咱們現在干的不就是這個嗎
What? Isn't this what we're doing now?
不是嗎
Isn't this what we're doing?
這兒  最后一盆  你要親手砸碎嗎
Here, this is the last one. You wanna do the honors?
不要
No?
行了  就這樣
Okay, then. That's that.
但愿你覺得有益身心
I hope it was therapeutic for you.
我不介意被批評  不是這回事
I don't mind being criticized, it's not that,
我只是覺得她要是這么堅持執行規定
I just think that if she's so set on enforcing the rules,
也許就不該在囚犯面前
then maybe she shouldn't undermine my authority
讓我難堪
in front of the inmates.
有些人用暴力管制  有些人則用魅力
Some of us control with muscle, some of us control with charm.
咱倆就是靠魅力的
You know, you and me, we're charm.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
記過配額指標爛透了
This whole shot quota's a bad idea.
對大家都不好受
It's making things harder for everyone.
還有一大堆文書工作
And all the friggin' paperwork.
我倒是不介意  給了我坐下來的時間
I don't mind the paperwork. Gives me a chance to get off my feet.
如果你忙著做文書工作  牢里打起架
But what if you're tied up doing paperwork and a fight breaks out
發生暴亂了怎么辦
and it turns into a prison riot?
你本可以阻止的  卻沒阻止成
And you could've stopped it, but you didn't,
因為你在辦公室做文書工作
because you were in your office doing paperwork?
你有沒有做過拯救全人類的英雄夢
You ever have those dreams where you save everybody?
有時吧
Sometimes.
有一次  我榮獲了國會榮譽勛章
One time, I received the Congressional Medal of Honor.
真厲害
Nice.
干什么
What?
有話快說  有屁快放
You got something to say, out with it.
我們認為記過配額指標不合理
We don't think the shot quota's reasonable.
對情況沒什么益處
It doesn't improve conditions.
會讓囚犯和獄警之間產生懷疑
It creates mistrust between the inmates and the staff.
你想讓她們相信你
You'd like them to trust you more?
我想讓她們認為
Well, I'd like them to think
她們受管束是公正的
that when they're disciplined, it's justified.
不然的話  誰還會照章辦事
I mean, otherwise, why follow the rules at all?
對我們也是如此
And the same goes for us.
我認為我被人吼是不公平的
I don't think it's fair that I was yelled at.
我要管理這座監獄
In order for me to run this facility,
你們所有人就得聽我指示行事
I need all of you to comply with my directives
不管你們認為合不合理
whether you find them "Reasonable" or not.
規矩是上面定下來的
The rules come from the top down.
但這些規矩
Yeah, but there are rules
我們根本就不嚴格執行
that we don't even enforce consistently.
卻被責怪...
And then we get blamed...
費歇爾  現在不是
Fischer! This is not the
適當的時機或地點來向我抱怨
appropriate time or place to air your complaint.
卡普托先生  抱歉  我是有話直說
Well, Mr. Caputo, I'm sorry, but I have to speak my mind.
你不能專橫地懲罰別人
You can't just punish someone
就為了殺雞儆猴...
arbitrarily to make an example of them...
你被解雇了
You're fired.
什么
What?
我警告過你了
I tried to warn you.
這個月的薪水會發給你
You'll be paid through the end of the month.
還有人強烈渴望直抒胸臆嗎
Does anyone else have the burning desire to speak their mind?
很好
Good.
白人妞  給我吧  我來就行
Oh, Blanca, Blanca, I got that. I got that. Damelo.
去洗攪拌器
Go clean the mixer.
那不是瑪麗薩干的嗎
拜托  那姑娘被關禁閉回來以后
Please. That girl's as useless as balls on a dildo
整個人跟假雞巴一樣廢
since she came back from seg.
她才待了多久  三分鐘
And she was there, what? Three minutes?
有事嗎
Can I help you?
給你帶了禮物
Brought you a gift.
我不需要陳年舊煙
I don't need no more stale-ass tobacco.
這算是補償  新貨  我保證
This is to make up for that. This is fresh, I promise.
在里面加了點薄荷  變成薄荷醇了
Put some peppermint in it, turned it into a menthol.
被獄警抓到了  你就要被記過了
CO catches you back here, you gonna get a shot.
你跟紅媽現在關系不錯啊
So, uh, you and, uh... you and Red on friendly terms now?
跟你無關
Doesn't concern you.
那女人還真知道怎么俘獲人心
Damn, that woman knows how to run a game on people.
我可以給你講幾個故事
I could tell you some stories.
你聽過
Hey, have you ever heard
蝎子和青蛙的寓言嗎
of the fable of the scorpion and the frog?
怎么  我他媽是青蛙嗎
What, I'm the fucking frog?
你倆狼狽為奸  我知道她在做些勾當
You two in cahoots. I know she's doing business.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你有賣家關系  她幫你散貨
You've got a vendor connection and she's handling your sales.
我只是來做飯的
I'm just here to cook.
紅媽干的事跟我毫無關系
Whatever Red's got going, got nothing to do with me.
要合伙人嗎
You want a partner?
我保證我比她更好
I promise I'm a much better bet,
因為紅媽只想要回她的廚房
because all Red wants is to get her kitchen back.
你給我好好聽著
You listen to me.
你自以為知道些什么  其實并沒有
Whatever you think you know, you don't.
我手不臟  沒破事
I'm keeping my hands clean, my shit polished.
我跟供應商或者非法贓物流入都沒關系
I got no connections with vendors or illegal swag coming through.
你們這些瘋婆娘我一個都不信
And I don't trust any of you crazy bitches.
你倆都他媽是蝎子
You're both fucking scorpions.
操  我操我操  媽逼
Shit. Shit, shit, shit. Fuck.
整體來看
Hey, listen, in the grand scheme of things,
香煙是什么
I mean, what's a cigarette, really?
就是卷在紙里的植物
You know, it's a plant and some paper.
你想想我可能會干的各種恐怖事件
When you think about all the horrible things I could be doing.
隨你抽吧  我無所謂了
Smoke all you want. I don't care anymore.
我被炒了
I got fired.
真好
Hey, good for you.
你不明白
You don't get it.
我現在該怎么辦  我沒有一技之長
What am I gonna do now? I'm not good at stuff.
你肯定不擅長這行
Well, for sure, you weren't great at this.
這可是褒獎你  相信我
But that reflects highly on you, trust me.
我有醫保和牙保  還在還我的起亞車貸
I had medical and dental. I was paying off my Kia.
你是個好人
You're a decent human being, you know.
脫離這個吸食靈魂的破地方
Getting canned from this soul-sucking pit
是你身上發生的最好的事
is the best thing that ever happened to you.
回家去  洗個熱水澡
Go home, take a hot bath,
開始找找專科學校
and start looking into technical colleges.
或者美容  學習腋窩和敏感區脫毛
Or cosmetology. Learn to wax armpits and vag lips.
外面大千世界等著你呢
There's a million things out there for you.
-我能問你一個問題嗎  -問吧
- Can I ask you a question? - Yeah, shoot.
前不久  你是在跟我調情嗎
Like, a while back, were you hitting on me?
不做夢就要死  對吧
We don't dream, we die, right?
我做得怎么樣
So, how'd I do?
我想了一下
I thought about it.
真的假的
Seriously?
騙你的
Not in a thousand years.
不過謝了
But thank you.
蘇珊  收拾東西離開這里
Susan, pack your shit and get the fuck out of here.
你會沒事嗎
Are you gonna be okay?
就這樣了
It is what it is.
寶貝  你被炒了
Babe, you got fired?
真糟
Lame.
讓我去看看他
Let me go see him.
我們得回去
We need to get back.
這是我越獄計劃的一部分
It's all part of my escape plan.
他會用眼淚轉移你的注意
He's going to distract you with his tears.
等我一下
Just give me a second.
簡直是詛咒
It's the fucking curse.
我拉你入伙  我沒吻你  但咱倆還是干了一票
I pull you in. I don't kiss you, but still, we did a job.
你在說什么呢
What are you talking about?
我說過  我生命中的男人全死了
I told you, all the men in my life die.
我不是你生命中的男人  好嗎
I'm not a man in your life. Okay?
你自己說的  我就是個小屁孩
You said so yourself, I'm a little shitpot.
你這么年輕怎么能死
You're too fucking young to die.
所以我不會死的
So I'm not gonna die.
我不用做化療了  我進入緩解期了
I'm done with chemo. I'm in remission.
羅莎  跟你一起很有意思
Listen, Rosa, it's been a lot of fun hanging out.
我受益良多
It's been a trip.
恭喜
Congratulations.
享受監獄
Enjoy prison.
享受生活  小屁孩
Enjoy your life, shitpot.
我該說什么
So, what should I say?
你說對了  我錯了
You was right, I was wrong?
應該跟你合伙的  我顯然沒法一個人干
Should've stuck with the band. I'm clearly not a solo artist.
但至少你還活著  詛咒沒克死你
But at least you're still alive. The curse never got you.
我從沒跟你事后吻過  也許就是這樣救了我
Well, I never did the after kiss. Maybe that's what saved me.
我為什么要那么做
Why did I do that?
你不想上我
You didn't wanna fuck me.
我想啊
Oh, but I did.
只是想在更大的錢床上
Just on a bigger bed of money.
我真貪婪
Greedy me.
我好想那氣味  唐尼
I miss the smell, Donny.
我愛現金的氣味
I love the smell of cash, man.
那種激情  表演  刺激
The excitement, the performance, the rush.
我在這里怎么找刺激啊
What am I gonna do in here for kicks?
查普曼一來就受到了
You know, Chapman been getting special treatment
特殊照顧
since the minute she got here.
她好像是第一個拿到休假的人
Figures she'd be the first to get furlough.
我真他媽浪費了
Man, I fucking blew it.
我離開了這破地方兩周
I had a solid two weeks out of this joint,
但一半時間都在找你這個逼
and I wasted half that time looking for your sorry ass.
去死  是你自己破壞了假釋條例
Fuck that. You done found time to violate your probation,
又滾回了這里
land your wide butt back up in here.
賤人  至少你還見過這圍欄之外的日光
Bitch, at least you seen daylight outside this fence.
我申請休假整整六個月
Man, I tried for six months to get furlough.
顯然一個死去的黑人老媽
Clearly a dead black mom
比不上一個病了的白人老太
ain't no competition for a sick, old white granny.
你和你家男人都不在一起了
You and your man aren't even together no more.
太浪費
What a waste.
要是我出去了  肯定和凱撒操一整天
If I got out, me and Cesar would be fucking all damn day.
我和迪艾保會沒日沒夜地操
Diablo and I would go all day and all night.
生病的奶奶
Sick abuela.
你他媽是怎么想到這個橋段的
The fuck you came up with that one?
天哪  查普曼  大家都恨透你了
Christ, Chapman, everybody hates your fucking guts.
是嗎  還有什么新消息
Yeah, what else is new?
嫉妒與死亡一樣強烈  所羅門之歌
"Jealousy is as fierce as the grave," Song of Solomon.
托妮·莫里森的嗎
Toni Morrison?
是《圣經》  親愛的
The Bible, sweetie.
這里人的爸媽過世了
Man, people's parents fucking go.
這里的病人得不到應有的照料
Got sick people in here who can't get proper treatment.
查普曼一生順風順水
Chapman ain't got no strife in her life,
但那賤人就是有一條康莊大道
but bitch gets the red carpet laid out for her.
歧視黑人啊
The new Jim Crow.
那賤人可能跪下了
Bitch probably got down on her knees.
含好了海利那粉粉的雞巴
Took a mouthful of that pink Healy dick.
是啊  我是白人
Yes, I am white!
大家都知道
We have established that.
我也拿到了休假
And I got furlough, too.
看來白人特權又贏了
I guess white privilege wins again.
作為整個白種人的發言人
And as a speaker for the entire white race,
我想說很遺憾你們受到了不公平待遇
I would like to say I am sorry that you guys got the raw deal,
但我他媽愛我奶奶
but I love my fucking grandmother.
是啊  她也有些白
And, yeah... yeah, she may be a whitey, too...
但她是個人
but she's a fucking person...
她病了
and she's sick...
她需要我
and she needs me!
都他媽給老娘閉上嘴
So shut the fuck up!
跟我沒關系
It's not my problem.
你和小維有矛盾  別扯上我
You and Vee got beef, don't drag me into your shit.
我以為波多黎各人討厭黑人呢
I thought Puerto Ricans hated black people.
我們也不喜歡俄羅斯人
We don't like Russians neither.
-她是個惡霸  -你倆都是
- She's a bully. - You're both fucking bullies
而我不信你們任何人
and I don't trust neither one of you.
我說了會幫你  我也幫了
Now I said that I will help you and I did.
但我不會卷入什么
But I am not gonna get caught up
黑白種人大混戰之中的
in the middle of some whitey versus blackie war.
你們都有黑歷史  我可不想跟你們有關系
Y'all got history, I want nothing to do with that.
我會盡快弄出去的
I'll get it out as soon as I can.
給你三天
You've got tres dias.
英文說就是"三天"
That's "Three days" In English.
是  夫人
Se, senora.
不過你就只能做到這份上嗎
In the meantime, is that really the best that you can do?
什么
What?
我救了你一命  賤人
I saved your ass, bitch.
你的東西  安全得很
Here's your shit, all safe and sound.
你想讓卡普托去你的溫室大鬧一場嗎
You want Caputo playing hot and cold in your greenhouse?
咱們現在就能去
'Cause we can go right
你那小小的種植系統
back to your little planter system right now.
行吧  算我謝你了
Okay, okay. I appreciate the gesture.
給我點時間等風頭過去
Give me a little time for things to cool down.
你要的東西來了
I've got your order coming.
交易還繼續
Deal's still on.
咱倆沒事吧  沒事
We're good, you and me, huh? We're good.
海利先生  我不能休假  我想退掉
Mr. Healy, I can't take my furlough. I wanna give it back.
這兒有人比我更需要
There are people here who are way more needy.
這兒有人的父母生病了
There are people here whose parents are sick.
-孩子們...  -天哪  你什么毛病
- Children... - For Christ's sake, what is with you?
我都不明白你這次為什么要幫我
Look, I don't even understand why you did this for me.
你討厭我  大家都不明白
You hate me! Nobody gets this!
查普曼  我早上
Chapman, I spent my morning
跟一位老太說她有末期癌癥
telling an old lady that she has terminal cancer
還有懲教署不會報銷她手術費用的
and that the DOC won't cover her surgery.
她說我沒用
And she said I was useless.
你知道嗎  她說得對
And you know what? She was right.
我開始這份工作時  充滿了理想
When I started this job, I was very idealistic.
我想做出些改變
I was gonna make a difference.
但我就是個弄文書的  我填表
But I'm a paper pusher. I fill out forms.
我做的大部分事就是保持你們安全整潔
Most of what I do is, I keep you safe and clean.
偶爾  就那么偶爾一次
And occasionally, once in a blue moon,
我會有個機會把表格申請上去
I get an opportunity to give one of those forms an extra nudge.
-多數人會感激  -我很感激
- Most people would be grateful. - I was.
真的
I am!
但現在我變成了眾矢之的
Until it turned me into a target!
不能退回休假
There's no taking back furlough.
你的車準備好以后
When your ride is ready,
你就能上車去看你生病的奶奶了
you be in that car on your way to see your sick grandmother.
姑娘們會竊竊私語  羨慕嫉妒
And girls will talk and they'll get jealous,
是的  她們甚至
and, yes, it's possible
可能會在你睡著時弄死你
they may even try to slock you in your sleep,
不過別理她們
but ignore them.
查普曼  人都有一死  錯過了就來不及了
Chapman, people die, and you don't get that moment back.
你得去見她  告訴她你有多愛她
So you go and see her and you tell her how much you love her
以及你多懊悔讓她失望了
and you tell her how sorry you are for letting her down.
得做到問心無愧
You clear your conscience.
重點是向她告別
This is about saying goodbye.
我給你這個機會  好好把握
I'm giving you that. Take it.
好吧  我會的
Okay, I will.
你這輔導員還不算太糟嘛
That wasn't bad. Your counseling.
你做得很好
You did a good job.
早安
Morning.
我給你帶了些盆栽
I brought you some plants.
看到它們現在在小盆里了嗎
They're in smaller pots, you see?
你要把它們種在這里面
You're gonna grow 'em in here?
不  是你來種
No, these are for you.
我才不把它們種這里面  我沒時間
Uh, I'm not gonna grow in here. I don't have the time.
我會找新的休閑方式
I'll find some other way to relax.
一定要讓紅媽收到  行嗎
Make sure Red gets those, okay?
如果你能有出獄一天的機會  你會想怎么使用
If you had one day on the outside, how would you spend it?
去我以前的市場  吃俄羅斯小餡餅
Oh... go to my market, taste the pirozhkis,
確保達米特里有繼續在好好做
make sure Dimitri hasn't let it all go to shit.
吃什么  俄羅斯小什么
The what? The piroso... Pirosis?
小餡餅
Pirozhkis.
含餡的餅  跟肉餅很像
Stuffed buns, like a meat pie.
我以前做這個很出名
I was famous for them.
周日的時候店門外會大排長龍呢
On Sunday there'd be a line out the door.
是我一周中最喜歡的日子
It was my favorite day.
我能想象到顧客們跟家人嬉笑怒罵
I'd imagine the families laughing, talking, fighting,
一邊吃著我的小餡餅
all while enjoying my pirozhkis.
店在皇后區  坐地鐵N號線很快能到
It's in Queens, a quick ride on the N train.
你會去嗎
Will you go?
去你的店嗎
To your place?
我要不是擔心  我也不會問
I wouldn't ask if I wasn't worried.
我希望有人能去幫我看看
I need someone to check it out,
點個三明治  看看店里
order a sandwich, take a look...
告訴我現在店里情況怎么樣
let me know how it's running.
你不能叫你兒子們看嗎
Can't you ask your sons?
我覺得他們沒跟我說實話
I don't think they're being honest with me.
我知道你家里有事
I know you have family business.
如果不是很重要  我也不會麻煩你
I wouldn't ask if it wasn't important.
我不確定...
I'm not sure if...
我得去醫院
I need to be at the hospital.
知道
Of course.
我不知道我有沒有空
I don't know if I'll have time.
但我有空會去看看的
I'll go if I can.
你有空再去就行了
Only if you have time.
怎么說來著  小仙冰
How do you say that? Pirosees?
-小餡餅  -小餡餅
- Pirozhkis. - Pirozhkis.
美味一絕
The best.
這里是怎么回事
Hell, what's with the back up?
拉丁妞們頭發太多了
Latin girls have a lot of hair.
你們這樣是不對的
This is not right.
你們不能逼我洗澡  我又沒有傷害到別人
You cannot force me to shower. I'm not hurting anybody.
我的鼻子不同意  而且收到四次投訴了
My nose would disagree, and four complaints have been filed.
規定里寫著得定期洗澡
It's in the rules. You shower regularly.
這定期是誰定的
Who determines what's regular?
天哪  去C區吧
Christ. Let's go to C Block.
不要  我拒絕
No, I refuse.
我現在是被動反抗
I am demonstrating passive resistance.
我們是主動出擊
We are demonstrating aggressive aggression.
寶佳康蒂[《風中奇緣》女主]  走吧
Let's go, Pocahontas.
-脫衣服  蘇蘇  -不要
- Off with it, Soso. - No!
賤人  你最好趕緊洗完
You better wash fast, bitch.
因為馬上就會涌出屎了
Because a shit storm coming up out of there any second now.
科杰克
Hey, hey, hey, Kojak.
昨天怎么樣了  有看到你的朋友嗎
How'd it go yesterday? Did you see your little friend?
他在緩解期
He's in remission.
這是好事  對吧
That's wonderful, right?
對他來說是好事
Wonderful for him.
別這樣  很快你也會沒事的
Come on. Soon you'll be gettin' your clean bill of health.
不  我很快就要死了
No, soon I'm gonna be dead.
我一直以為自己會是在一片火光
I always pictured myself going out in a blaze of glory.
槍聲四起  汽車爆沖的情景下離開
Hail of gunfire, screech of tires.
但這種死法
But this kind of death...
緩慢又看不見地
this slow, invisible...
讓我的生命慢慢流逝
disappearing into nothing...
太可怕了
It's terrifying.
我要繼續睡覺了
I'm gonna go back to sleep now.
這化療讓我精疲力盡
The chemo, it wipes me out.
你睡吧
Yeah. You do that.
喂
Hello?
媽  天哪  昨天我一直
Mom! God, I've been trying
想聯系你們呢
to get in touch with you guys for the past day.
我被準假了
My furlough went through!
帕波
Piper?
我需要爸爸的車牌號  或者卡爾的
So, I need Daddy's license plate number or Cal's.
誰會來  還要一套換洗衣物
Who's coming? And, uh, a change of clothes.
-帕波  -換洗衣物
- Piper? - A change of clothes.
叫萊瑞把藍色毛衣拿來  好像在波麗家
Um, tell Larry the blue sweater. I think it's at Polly's.
奶奶走了
Grandmother's gone.
她昨晚去世了
She passed last night.
但我要出去了
But I'm getting out.
親愛的
Honey?
我錯過了
I missed it.
你的精神與她同在
You were there in spirit.
帕波
Piper?
什么事  喬
Yes, Joe?
我昨天炒了費歇爾
I terminated Fischer yesterday.
她要拿到這個月的薪水
She needs to get paid through the end of the month.
你一定覺得很難受
That must've been hard for you.
別說了  我們本來就人手不足  她有可取之處
Please don't start. We're already understaffed. She had value.
你一定是這么認為的
I suppose you must've thought so.
我們不會被告性騷擾吧
We're not gonna get stuck with a sexual harassment suit, are we?
很好  至于人手問題
Good. As for the staffing issue,
我明白找到高質量人員不容易
I understand it's hard to find quality people.
在這個環境當中
It takes a certain kind of je
需要難以明說的品質增強效率
ne sais quoi to be effective in this environment.
"難以明說的品質"不會總是工作18小時的
"Je ne sais quoi" Doesn't always work for 18 an hour.
我聘用我能找到的最佳人選
I hire the best people I can find.
我知道你事情多
I know, and you're overwhelmed.
但我們需要更多人手  我會幫你找的
But we need some more muscle in here. I'm gonna help you out.
我自己來就行  謝了
I'll do my own hiring. Thank you.
已經幫你搞定了
It's already been taken care of.